Finding Aid for the Abraham Polonsky papers, 1946-1999 (bulk 1970s-1990s) LSC.2233
UCLA Library Special Collections
Abraham Polonsky papers
1946-1999, (bulk 1970s-1990s)
1970-1990
UCLA Library Special Collections
Polonsky, Abraham
LSC.2233
10.9 Linear Feet (18 boxes, 2 record cartons, and 1 flat box)
Abraham Polonsky was a director, screenwriter and novelist. In 1951, he refused to confirm or deny membership to the Communist party before the House Un-American Activities Committee and as a result, he was blacklisted by the entertainment industry. The collection consists of script material, manuscripts, books, and a small amount of clippings, photographs, correspondence, and other ephemera reflecting Polonsky's activities from the 1970s-1990s.
Restrictions on Access
Open for research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
Provenance/Source of Acquisition
Gift of Susan Polansky Epstein and Henry Polansky, 2000.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 9968403613606533
Biography
Abraham Lincoln Polonsky was born December 5, 1910. He graduated from the City College of New York and Columbia University Law School, and for a while, he taught English at City College. Before trying starting his career in film, Polonsky wrote novels and several short stories. During the 1940s he also wrote for radio and worked with the Columbia Workshop and Orson Welles. During World War II, Polonsky was assigned to the Office of Strategic Studies, a forerunner of the Central Intelligence Agency.
He moved to the West Coast in the mid-1940s. Polonsky's first two produced screenplays, Golden Earrings and Body and Soul, were released in 1947 and he was nominated for an Academy Award for Body and Soul. Not long after, Polonsky directed his first movie, Force of Evil (1948). During the late 1940s, he also became an editor of the journal, Hollywood Quarterly.
In the early 1950's, Polonsky refused to testify about his Communist Party affiliations or name party members before the House Un-American Activities Committee and was subsequently fired by Twentieth Century Fox and blacklisted. With only a few film titles to his credit, the Polonsky name did not appear in any film credit again for almost two decades. It was not until 1969 that he directed his second film, Tell Them Willie Boy Is Here.
Polonsky moved back to New York, and using pseudonyms wrote for television shows such as You Are There and the series Danger. During the 1950s he wrote the novel, A Season of Fear and co-wrote the 1959 film Odds Against Tomorrow, which was attributed to John O. Killens. Years later, as a leader in the fight to have credits restored to blacklisted filmmakers, Polonsky earned his own credit for that screenplay in 1996 from the Writers Guild of America.
In the 1990s, Polonsky helped write the McCarthy-era docudrama Guilty by Suspicion and appeared around the country in programs observing the anniversary of the blacklist. He also taught cinema classes at the University of Southern California and California State Northridge. To commemorate his film work, the Los Angeles Film Critics Association selected Polonsky a co-winner of the group's 1998 career achievement award. Polonsky died October 29, 1999 in Beverly Hills, California.
Scope and Content
The collection consists of materials related to the career of Abraham Polonsky. Includes script material, manuscripts, books, and a small amount of clippings, publications, photographs, correspondence, audio and videotapes and other ephemera reflecting Polonsky's activities from circa 1970s-1990s. Script material includes writings for Body of Fear, Childhood's End, Cold War and Force of Evil, among others. The clippings and publications feature writings about Polonksy, his work, or the Blacklist. The books are a mix of publications given to and/or collected by Polonsky.
Organization and Arrangement
Arranged alphabetically according to file and publication titles.
Related Material
Abraham Polonsky Papers. Wisconsin Center for Film and Theater Research.
Motion picture producers and directors -- United States -- Archives.; Screenwriters -- United States -- Archives.; Polonsky, Abraham -- Archives
- 50 Years Ago SAG Remembers the Blacklist issue of Screen Actor, 1998 Jan (Box 10, Folder 10)
- Abraham Lincoln Brigade - pamphlet, 1995 Feb 26 (Box 7, Folder 3)
- Abraham Lincoln Polonsky bibliography, no date (Box 11, Folder 13)
- Abraham Polonsky and the Politics of Film - manuscript by Dave Wagner and Paul Buhle, no date (Box 10, Folder 8)
- Abraham Polonsky photographs (3 items), no date (Box 13, Folder 15)
  Scope and Contents note
  Photographs include Polonsky: in front of poster of Body and Soul; at unknown symposium; and receiving honorary degree at California State University Northridge.
- Abraham Polonsky, the Filmmaker as Novelist (Introduction), 1998 May (Box 13, Folder 10)
  With note from Paul Buhle. Appears to be introduction to The World Above
- Advice and Planning by Martin H. Krieger - book, c. 1981 (Box 19)
  Inscribed by author.
- Afterwords by Polonsky (2 copies), no date (Box 10, Folder 12)
- Alvah Bessie's Short Fictions- book, c. 1982 (Box 19)
- American Movie Classics Blacklist: Hollywood on Trail - videotape [probably Blacklist: Hollywood on Trial], 1996 (Box 16)
  Restricted access: Use of moving image material requires production of viewing copies.
- Among the Survivors: A novel by Tamara Hovey - book, c. 1971 (Box 19)
- An Evening with Abraham Polonsky write up in Point of View newsletter, 1992 (Box 10, Folder 13)
- Analysis of Math - chapter manuscript by Martin Krieger, 1998 Nov 12 (Box 10, Folder 2)
- Annotated manuscript pages (no title), no date (Box 9, Folder 7)
- Annotated manuscript pages (no title), 1990 (Box 9, Folder 6)
- Articles about Polonsky in French (photocopies), 1967 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  From Postif and Cahiers du Cinema
- Articles and tear outs regarding works by Polonsky, 1970s - 1990s (Box 14, Folder 2)
  Body and Soul, Force of Evil, Guilty by Omission, Tell Them Willie Boy is Here, Romance of a Horse Thief and Zenia's Way.
- Articles written John Howard Lawson (photocopies) (Box 8, Folder 18)
- Assassination on Embassy Row - outline, no date (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Assorted clippings, 1985, 1996, 1998 (Box 14, Folder 4)
- Assorted clippings related to Polonksy, 1970s, 1990s (Box 14, Folder 3)
- Assorted Correspondence to Polonsky, 1990s (Box 14, Folder 11)
- Best Years of Our Lives (review) by Polonsky reprinted from the Hollywood Quarterly, 1947 April (Box 8, Folder 17)
  Two copies.
- Birthday greetings to Polonsky (hand-made, oversized), no date (Box 20, Folder 3)
- Black Corridor: Abraham Polonsky's Long Journey (The) - edited by John Schultheiss and Sally Schultheiss, 1991 (Box 9, Folder 3)
- Body and Soul (flip side Fine Dinner) - audio cassette recording, no date (Box 16)
  Restricted access: Use of audio material requires production of listening copies.
- Body and Soul - novelization by Sam Merwin Jr. for Century Books, 1947 (Box 8, Folder 8)
- Body and Soul - photocopy of shooting script final, 1947 Jan 13 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Body and Soul - photocopy of shooting script final (2 copies), 1947 Jan 13 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Body and Soul - script written by Polonsky, no date (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Booklets about various screenwriters, no date (Box 12, Folder 9)
  Abraham Polonsky, Ring Lardner, Jr., Ernest Lehman, Julius J. Epstein, Stewart Stern and Philip Dunne.
- Bread and a Stone by Alvah Bessie - book, c. 1948 (Box 19)
- Bright Lights, Big City: A Novel by Jay McInerney - book, c. 1984 (Box 19)
  Inscribed by Ron.
- California State University Northridge Radio-Television-Film Department appreciation plaque, 1992 Oct 1 (Box 14, Folder 13)
- Case of David Smith (The) by Polonsky reprinted from the Hollywood Quarterly, 1946 Jan (Box 8, Folder 17)
- Childhood 's End - screenplay by Polonsky, 1974 Apr 16 (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Childhood's End - annotated script, no date (Box 7, Folder 11)
- Childhood's End - screenplay by Polonsky, 1974 Apr 16 (Box 7, Folder 10)
- Cold War - annotated script and story pages, no date (Box 3, Folder 7)
  See also Season of Fear.
- Cold War (Folder 1 of 2), 1987 May 26 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  Loose script pages, some annotated. Possible second draft with pages from In This Time and Age.
- Cold War - original screenplay by Polonsky, 1987 Jan 5 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  Title page annotated with In This Time and Age second draft.
- Cold War - rough notes, no date (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Cold War - screenplay, 1987 Jan 5 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Cold War - second draft screenplay by Polonsky, 1987 May 26 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Cold War (Folder 2 of 2), no date (Box 6, Folder 3)
- Cold War script material by Polonsky, no date (Box 3, Folder 2)
  Envelope annotated first typed draft plus written typed changes for second. See also Season of Fear.
- Collected Plays by Sean O'Casey - book, c. 1951 (Box 19)
- Communist Infiltration of Hollywood Motion Picture - Part 1, 1951 Mar 21 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  Appears to be part of larger publication. Photocopy. United States House of Representatives Committee on Un-American Actitivies. Public Hearing.
- Communist Influence in Hollywood by John Weber, no date (Box 11, Folder 7)
- Consciousness and Content In Film, Literature, and Science, no date (Box 11, Folder 14)
  Articles compiled for class taught by Polonsky.
- Content and Consciousness course taught by Polonsky at USC outline and memo of confirmation, 1989 Fall (Box 10, Folder 4)
- Day in Regensburg (A) by Joseph Opatoshu - book, c. 1968 (Box 18)
  Inscribed by David Opatoshu.
- Directing the Film: Film Directors on their Art by Erick Sherman - book, c. 1976 (Box 18)
  Polonsky mentioned in book.
- Discoverers (The) - novel manuscript, no date (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Dreams and Dead Ends: The American Gangster/Crime Film by Jack Shadoian - book, c. 1977 (Box 18)
- Eden Regained - typed manuscript pages with annotations, no date (Box 8, Folder 10)
- Eight Famous Elizabethan Plays - book, c. 1932 (Box 18)
- Film as Literature Series at California State University press release, no date (Box 12, Folder 2)
- Film in the Forties: Programme 5 - audio cassette recording, 1995 Mar 23 (Box 17)
  Restricted access: Use of audio material requires production of listening copies. See box 17 for letter to Polonsky from Mark Burman.
- Film Society of Lincoln Center programs (3 items), 1996 - 1998 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  With letter regarding Polonsky question and
- Flyers for Polonsky film showings, 1997 (Box 14, Folder 10)
- Force of Evil - photocopy of shooting script by Polonsky and Ira Wolfert, 1948 May 25 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Force of Evil - annotated photocopy of shooting script by Polonsky and Ira Wolfert, 1948 May 25 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  Titled Tucker's People.
- Force of Evil - incomplete annotated photocopy of shooting script by Polonsky and Ira Wolfert, 1948 May 25 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  The title Tucker's People crossed out on title
- Force of Evil - John Schultheiss commentary, no date (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Force of Evil - shooting script by Polonsky and Ira Wolfert, 1948 May 25 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Force of Evil - shooting script by Polonsky and Ira Wolfert (2 copies), 1948 May 25 (Box 11, Folder 1)
- Force of Evil shooting and continuity screenplay synthesis (possible Film as Literature Series), no date (Box 12, Folder 4)
- Force of Evil: The Critical Edition (The) - by Polonsky (2 hardcover books), c. 1996 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Founders and Reformers by Kim Fellner in Screen Actor, 1979 (Box 13, Folder 6)
- Gladiators - annotated script, no date (Box 7, Folder 1)
- Great Shows by Larry Ceplair in Emmy magazine (article about You Are There), 1982 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  Article inscribed to Polonsky from Charles.
- Green Corn Rebellion - research, 1978 Dec 12 (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Gush Etzion and the Hebron Hills, no date (Box 13, Folder 13)
- Handwritten notes and newsletter found among Polonsky's books, 1986, 1995, 1998 (Box 14, Folder 5)
- Hanging on in Paradise by Fred Lawrence Guiles - book, c. 1975 (Box 19)
- Hemingway and Chaplin by Abraham Polonsky, no date (Box 11, Folder 12)
- Hollywood at its Worst in The Sunday Times Magazine, 1991 May 19 (Box 20, Folder 4)
- Hollywood Directors and Their Craft - videotape recording, no date (Box 16)
- Hollywood Education: Tales of Movie Dreams and Easy Money (A) by David Freeman - book, c. 1986 (Box 18)
- Hollywood Exile: Or How I Learned to Love the Blacklist - presskit, no date (Box 10, Folder 15)
- Hollywood Remembers the Blacklist event program and thank you letter, 1997 Oct 27 (Box 11, Folder 3)
- Hollywood Screenwriters and their Craft transcript, no date (Box 11, Folder 15)
- Hollywood Social Problem Film: Madness, Despair, and Politics from the Depression to the Fifties (The) by Peter Roffman and Jim Purdy - book, c. 1981 (Box 18)
- Hollywood, Psychotherapy and the McCarthy Era: The Secret of Sigmund Freud Versus the Pink Shrink Fink by Benjamin Harris, 1996 Nov 18 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  Invited address at the American Psycyological Association. Sent to Polonsky by Harris.
- Holograph pages of notes (Box 15, Folder 4)
- Horses, Cossack, Jews On Film by David Platt in Jewish Currents, 1971 Oct (Box 10, Folder 14)
  Review of Romance of a Horsethief.
- Idiolects Writing on Film magazine (No. 12), 1982 (Box 12, Folder 1)
- In the Worst of Times, It was the Best of Times - first draft of manuscript by Charles Russell (2 photocopies), no date (Box 9, Folder 4)
- Indio Trash Compactor Murders (The) by Michael Shepler - book, c. 1979 (Box 18)
- Interview with Abraham Polonsky, no date (Box 12, Folder 7)
  Transcript with notes possibly from interview with Eric Sherman. Letter from Film Quarterly and notes from Bill Pechter regarding time spent with Polonsky.
- Interview with Polonksy, no date (Box 10, Folder 6)
  Appears to be for BBC.
- Interview with Polonsky at Los Feliz theater, 1977 (Box 7, Folder 4)
- Interview with Polonsky regarding Marty Ritt, 1977 (Box 7, Folder 5)
- Introduction written by Lumet about Polonsky, 1997 (Box 8, Folder 5)
- It was the Worst of Times, It was the Best of Times - first draft of manuscript by Charles Russell, no date (Box 11, Folder 2)
- Jamaica Talk: Three Hundred Years of the English Language in Jamaica by Frederic G. Cassidy - book, c. 1961 (Box 19)
- Joseph Losey: Vainottu Muukalainen by Matti Salo - book, c. 1989 (Box 19)
  Inscribed by author. Polonsky mentioned in book.
- Journal of Leo Tolstoi (The) - book (First Volume, 1895-1899), c. 1917 (Box 19)
- Karen Holden poetry, no date (Box 10, Folder 9)
- Keepers of the Flame: Unofficial Artists of Leningrad curated and edited by Selma Holo exhibit catalogue, 1990 - 1991 (Box 13, Folder 14)
  Inscribed by curator and editor.
- Kiss of the Spider Woman by Manuel Puig - book, c. 1978 (Box 18)
  Inscribed with unreadable signature.
- Kuleshov on Film: Writings of Lev Kuleshov - book, c. 1974 (Box 18)
  Inscribed by Ronald Levaco.
- Last Season - script notes, no date (Box 8, Folder 15)
- Letter to Polonsky from Dave Wagner, 1996 Jan 2 (Box 17, Folder 2)
  Originally found with videotape of Red Hollywood in box 16.
- Letter to Polonsky from Mark Burman, 1995 Apr 18 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  Originally found cassette Film in the Forties: Programme 5 addressed to Polonsky in Box 17.
- Life of Samuel Johnson (The) by James Boswell (Vol. 1 and 2) - books, no date (Box 18)
- Lives of the Hunted by Ernest Thompson Seton - book, c. 1967 (Box 18)
  Inscribed with unreadable signature. Moved letter from Craig to Box 14, Folder 5.
- Lives of the Poets: Six Stories and a Novella by E.L. Doctorow - book, c. 1984 (Box 19)
- Lobsterback Boston Massacre - annotated outline, no date (Box 7, Folder 9)
- Loose annotated script pages (no title), no date (Box 9, Folder 9)
- Loose manuscript pages (no title), no date (Box 9, Folder 8)
- Los Angeles Film Critics Association career achievement award correspondence, 1998 - 1999 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  With copies of testimonials from Robert Redford and Martin Scorsese and congratulatory letter Allen Garfield.
- Los Angeles Film Critics Association honors Epstein and Polonsky article in Hollywood Reporter and Daily Variety, 1998 Oct 19 (Box 8, Folder 2)
- Made In the Fade by Patricia Mellencamp in Cine Tracts: A Journal of Film and Cultural Studies, 1981 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  Article inscribed to Polonsky by Mellencamp.
- Manifesto for Cyborgs (A) - essay by Donna Haraway, no date (Box 8, Folder 7)
- Mario the Magician - script covers only, no date (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Martin Krieger article on Math, no date (Box 11, Folder 4)
- Martin Scorsese: Scene by Scene - videotape recording, no date (Box 16)
- Marxism and Literature by Raymond Williams - book, c. 1977 (Box 18)
- Matti Salo correspondence, 1990 - 1991 (Box 13, Folder 2)
- Matti Salo letter drafts, 1988 Jul 16 (Box 9, Folder 2)
- Matti Salo Questions and Answers, no date (Box 13, Folder 3)
- Michael Shepler poetry, 1986 (Box 15, Folder 3)
- Much Ado About Nothing the Making of the Movie by Kenneth Branagh - book, c. 1993 (Box 14, Folder 7)
- Musta Kaytava: Abraham Polonsky Pitka Vaellus by Matti Salo -book, c. 1991 (Box 19)
- Mysteries and Scandals: The Hollywood Blacklist - videotape, 1999 May 19 (Box 16)
- National Society of Film Critics on Movie Comedy (The) - book, c. 1977 (Box 19)
- Nature of the Universe (The) by Fred Hoyle - book, c. 1950 (Box 18)
  Inscribed by Lester Cole.
- New Life Options: The Working Woman's Resource Book by Rosalind K. Loring and Herbert A. Otto, c. 1976 (Box 18)
  Inscribed by Toni.
- No Other Way by Polonsky - annotated photocopy of manuscript, no date (Box 6, Folder 4)
- No Stone Unturned: An Almanac of North American prehistory by Louis A. Brennan - book, c. 1959 (Box 18)
  Removed letter from Gertrude to Box 14, Folder 5. Donor unsure if the book is a first edition.
- Notes from the Gallows by Julius Fuchik - book, c. 1948 (Box 18)
  Removed letter (postcard) from Ec[k]ardt to Box 14, Folder 5.
- Odds Against Tomorrow - screenplay by John O. Killens, no date (Box 7, Folder 2)
- Odds Against Tomorrow motion picture soundtrack - audio cassette tape, c. 1991 (Box 16)
- Odds Against Tomorrow: Film Noir Without Linguistic Irony by John Schultheiss, no date (Box 12, Folder 5)
- Odds Against Tomorrow: The Critical Edition by Polonksy edited by John Schultheiss (Film as Literature Series), no date (Box 12, Folder 3)
- One Fine Day - notes, no date (Box 8, Folder 9)
- Outline (no title) - 3 pages, no date (Box 8, Folder 14)
- Part III - typed manuscript, no date (Box 7, Folder 8)
  Starts on page 342. Possible novel, no title page or credit.
- Paul Goodman and the New York Jews by Taylor Stoehr from Salmagundi, 1985 Winter-Spring (Box 11, Folder 11)
  Inscribed to Polonsky by Taylor.
- Paul Rissient on Paul Jarrico, 1997 Dec (Box 11, Folder 9)
  Possible speech.
- Paul Verlaine: Selected Poems -book, c. 1948 (Box 18)
- Piece de Resistance - annotated play by Polonsky, no date (Box 5, Folder 6)
- Piece de Resistance - annotated playscript by Polonsky, no date (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Piece de Resistance - play by Polonsky, 1957 (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Piece de Resistance - play by Polonsky, no date (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Piece de Resistance - playscript by Polonsky, c. 1957 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Piece de Resistance - playscript by Polonsky, c. 1957 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Piece de Resistance - poster, no date (Box 20, Folder 2)
- Piece de Resistance - press release, playbill and placards, no date (Box 5, Folder 4)
- Piece de Resistance - production bills and expenses, 1981 (Box 6, Folder 1)
- Piece de Resistance - production contact sheet, no date (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Piece de Resistance - unbound annotated pages, no date (Box 5, Folder 7)
- Pinko stinko: 50 years later in Variety Weekly, 1996 Sept 9-15 (Box 20, Folder 4)
- Plan for Story - outline and budget, no date (Box 8, Folder 13)
- Poems and Prophecies of William Blake (The) - book, no date (Box 18)
- Poetry by various authors, 1987, 1997 (Box 15, Folder 2)
- Politics of Force of Evil - article by Christine Brinkman with letter, 1980 Feb 15 (Box 7, Folder 13)
- Polonsky and Kazan by Terence Butler in Sight and Sound International Film Quarterly, 1988 Autumn (Box 13, Folder 7)
- Polonsky Pick-ups (23) - videotape recording, no date (Box 16)
- Polonsky transcriptions, 1970, 1993, 1997 (Box 14, Folder 1)
- Quarterly Journal of the Library of Congress (The), 1978 Jul (Box 13, Folder 12)
  With promotion record LPs on inside cover.
- Red Hollywood - videotape recording, no date (Box 17)
- Red Hollywood by Thom Andersen and Noel Burch - videotape recording, no date (Box 16)
- Red Hollywood by Thom Anderson and Noel Burch for Abraham Polonsky - videotape recording, no date (Box 17)
  See box 17 for letter to Polonsky from Dave
- Report on Blacklisting: I Movies by John Cogley - book, c. 1956 (Box 18)
- Reporting World War II: Part One American Journalism 1938-1944 - book, c. 1995 (Box 19)
- Reporting World War II: Part Two American Journalism 1944-1946 - book, c. 1995 (Box 19)
- Revival - screenplay by Sheldon Star, no date (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Romance of a Horsethief original motion picture soundtrack - LP (2 copies) (Box 21)
- Round Eyes in the Middle Kingdom - presskit, 1996 Feb 20 (Box 17, Folder 3)
- Round Eyes in the Middle Kingdom - videotape recording, no date (Box 17)
- Rubaiyat of Omar Khayyam by Edward Fitzgerald - book, c. 1995 (Box 18)
  Removed note from Morteza Negahi to Box 14, Folder 5.
- Salt of the Earth and Breaking Ground by Paul Jarrico and Herbert J. Biberman in The California Quarterly, 1953 Summer (Box 13, Folder 11)
- San Francisco International Film Festival - contact sheets with shots of Polonsky, no date (Box 11, Folder 6)
- San Francisco International Film Festival (39th) - program, 1996 (Box 10, Folder 3)
- San Francisco International Film Festival (41st) - program, 1998 (Box 11, Folder 5)
- Screenplay: A Blend of Film Form and Content by Margaret Mehring (The) - book, c. 1990 (Box 19)
- Screenwriting for Narrative Film and Television by William Miller - book, c. 1980 (Box 19)
- Screenwriting: The Art, Craft and Business of Film and Television Writing by Richard Walter - book, c. 1988 (Box 19)
- Season of Fear - annotated screenplay by Polonsky, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  Title page annotated fourth version. See also Cold War.
- Season of Fear - annotated screenplay pages by Polonsky, no date (Box 3, Folder 1)
  With note. See also Cold War
- Season of Fear - annotated screenplay pages by Polonsky, no date (Box 2, Folder 7)
  See also Cold War.
- Season of Fear - fourth version screenplay by Polonsky, 1987 Nov 18 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Season of Fear - screenplay pages by Polonsky, no date (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Season of Fear - script pages, no date (Box 2, Folder 8)
  Appears to be Season of Fear. See also Cold
- Season of Fear - third version script, 1987 Nov 18 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  Annotated formerly Cold War.
- Season of Fear -annotated screenplay pages by Polonsky, no date (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Siegfried's Journey 1916 - 1920 by Siegfried Sassoon - book, c. 1947 (Box 18)
- South Bank Show "Sundance" - videotape recording, 1989 Feb 23 (Box 16)
- Star Acting: Gish, Garbo, Davis by Charles Affron - book, c. 1977 (Box 19)
- Stories in Their Minds (The) in USC Trojan Family, 1989 Feb-March (Box 20, Folder 4)
- Sweet Land - original screenplay by Polonsky (2 copies), 1968 Oct 18 (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Talking Pictures by Richard Corliss - photocopy of chapter about Polonsky, c. 1974 (Box 7, Folder 12)
- Ted Kopple's Nightline (blacklisting) - videotape recording, 1999 Mar 19 (Box 16)
- Tell Them Willie Boy Is Here - program, 1970 Jan (Box 13, Folder 4)
  In Film bill (movie program magazine).
- Test of Character in Starlog, 1989 Dec (Box 8, Folder 6)
  About Jeff Corey.